Raghava ...
Raghava , today too , you will leave the work incomplete .
Is there a wedding in the house that you need to be so particular ?
Just apply four strokes with the brush on these walls .
And quickly run around and polish these teak furniture .
That 's all I 've told you to do .
But you have been in this house with your broom and brush since
the last few days .
It 's not that there are no other painters in this village .
But the people here believe that Maadampally house , is haunted
... with witches and dare not to step in here .
You were brave enough to come so I entrusted you with the job .
But if you are bent on cheating me then there will be trouble .
Sharadamma from Calcutta will be here any minute now .
Are you planning to stay here with your broom until then ?
Let me tell you one thing , do as much as you can today and stop .
After that I don 't want you loitering here for this purpose .
I won 't pay you any wages for that then .
Can 't you hear me ?
I wonder where he is ... Is he hiding somewhere painting ...
Raghava ...
Rajappa ...
My God ...
My umbrella ...
Vaidyare ...
The letter for you is va ... do you know any song starting with va ...
I know a lot of things with va ... I 've been calling you for long ,
If you happen to see Dasappankutty , ask him to come
home to take out the bucket which fell into the well .
Don 't forget ...
Had been to Maadampally house that 's why I am late .
Your daughter had been here , she just left from here .
Is that all . Now what 's happening here ...
I just asked Warrior to tell me a song starting with the letter pa ...
Then ... did he sleep over it ... - Yes . And I gave him Ta .
Then ... here it is ...
Without taking the key at dawn from the ...
Wait ... say that ... without giving the key ...
Yes , of course ... Without taking the key at ...
It 's not like that , what 's wrong with you today ?
I have not taken it , that 's all ...
I 've forgotten to take the key from Maadampally house .
Dasappa , that girl from the Thekkedath house has been
looking for you . She said that a bucket has fallen into the well .
I know of it . I am going there now .
Who 's it ?
Oh it 's you ! - Where are you going ?
I was on the way to your place . Has it been taken out ?
No , but how come you know of it ?
Our vaidyar told me . You should have sent Alli to me earlier .
But I haven 't been to the house as yet .
Then come . Well go together and get it out .
Are you not afraid of going out at night ?
Me , of course not . Are you afraid ?
Not at all . I thought of taking it tomorrow
but I won 't get sleep until I take it .
It 's the heat . I 'll take it out and give it to you .
Once you pour few mugs of water over you , you 'll feel better
If only I could get a shovel from some where ... - A shovel , what for ?
That 's not necessary , III get into the well .
But why do you have to enter a well to take out the key from
Maadampally house .
If you take the key , then what about the bucket ?
Bucket ! What bucket ? - The bucket that fell into the well .
What 's wrong with you , you kept on saying , you 'll take it out .
Are you trying to fool me ? You just come with me now .
Where are we going ?
Didn 't you understand ? ... to Maadampally house .
At this time of night . I thought we were going to take out
the bucket .
You don 't have to think a lot just come with me .
On which day were you born ?
A Friday . - Oh ! So , afraid . Is it ?
Talk softly ...
If you are afraid , just sing a song . I am going to sing one .
I 'll kill you .
Hey ... - What 's it ? - Who has opened the door ?
Just take the key ...
Who is going there , Dasappa ?
Yesterday night the person you saw at Maadampally is trapped
inside . You wait here . It 's none else than that Tamilian lady .
The fact that you did not wait there was because of your luck .
I 've made these Talismans after praying .
I am scared - There 's nothing to fear .
Nothing at all . My talismans are very effective .
Without uttering a word , tie them to the four corners of the house .
I want to urgently go to the loo .
- Go ...
Yesterday night you were so afraid , it 's shameful .
A man has to be in control of his senses . He must be brave .
Anyway since I was present , let no one hear of this event .
Are you hungry ? What is it ?
I want to use the toilet
Sister ...
What 's it , Dasappa ?
I have been calling out to you for so long .
Did brother tell you anything today ? I mean tell you ?
To me , no ... Why do you ask ?
Then brother has had this illness for some time now .
Why , what happened ? He went out in the morning without
telling me a thing .
That 's exactly how he is even now , he is not saying a word .
No other illness .
Not speaking . I want to see him this minute .
Has he been taken to a hospital ?
No , he is in the toilet .
In the toilet ! - Yes , there 's nothing to fear . Come along .
What senseless things are you saying ?
Yesterday night he got a scare at Maadampally . I told him not to
go alone if he is afraid and that III come along .
Yesterday what happened at that house , you never said anything .
How are you feeling now ?
You can 't speak . Oh , God !
What 's all this you are doing ?
Did you see ...
Oh God , what will I do ? Leave him . I shall go to big brother .
I 'll ask him to give you a talisman . Leave me ...
No need of any talisman , all he needs is an electric shock .
He got scared .
Yes , that 's what Dasappan said . He is just not answering me .
If you could chant something and give it to me ...
He may have entered there at an unsafe hour saying hymns .
He couldn 't sleep without taking charge of the inheritance of
those people from Calcutta . And now what happened ?
He filled Sharadamma 's ears with tales and took the
key to that house from me .
Long ago famous Tantrics have chanted powerful chants and
have exorcised the place and trapped the haunting spirits
in a room . Your husband is new to this place .
I told him not to have anything to do with the house .
He never listened to me .
Okay , I 'll give you an enchanted thread . But will he tie it .
Yes ... - Then come .
Give it to me ... I came first .
Without speaking a word go and tie it .
Hey , you will tear it ... I told you !
What 's happening there ? - Nothing ...
Hey , look who 's here !
Ganga , that 's uncle .
I thought only sister Sharada was coming .
I had no idea you were coming too .
So , where are the others ?
We came alone , there 's no one else . Meet Ganga .
Yesterday we arrived very late from Trivandrum .
We did not want to disturb you so we went to Maadampally .
You two stayed there alone yesterday night .
Well , I saw the key in the door , so I asked Ganga to wait outside
... while I went in to check if anyone was home .
No one was there . - Then what did you do ?
I thought it was too late to wake you all .
So we rented a room in the town .
Well , who is this ... do you know us ?
How is that possible . Nakul has never brought you here after
you were married .
Well , ask him when was the last time he came here .
Ganga , this is my aunt , this is her daughter Jayshree .
How are you ? How you have grown !
She 's Alli . My uncles daughter .
Hey , aunt you ! Too are here . What is the occasion ? How 's uncle ?
What ?
Okay , don 't say a word . Just go and tie it on him .
That is a talisman for your uncle . That 's why she is silent .
That is uncle 's eldest daughter , Sreedevi .
Did my aunt not come with you ?
She was to , but my sister came and took her to Bombay .
Anyway nowadays who wants their ancestral house .
Don 't worry , I 've planned to stay here for a few days .
Until the work on the new plant gets over , well stay here .
That 's nice . Come , dear !
I assume you will be here for 3 to 4 months . - Almost .
Then you can stay here with us .
No uncle , well stay at Maadampally .
At Maadampally - Yes , why ?
It 's true that Maadampally is your ancestral home and your mother
is entitled to a share in it but that house is not good for staying .
That house is haunted since some time .
You may have heard of it in your childhood .
There have been many untimely deaths there .
Girls from outside families who stay there after marriage are
harassed ... Ganga is a girl from another family
These are all very outdated rumors . Who believes them now ?
You don 't have to worry because I told you .
If you have decided to stay there , go ahead .
You can go round and see everything .
You , come here .
Now I have a few words to say to you ...
Did you think I 've lost my tongue ? - No
So your illness has disappeared .
Yes it has . I shall remove any other illness I had in the morning
What did you say ? I should be given an electric shock .
Who do you think you are to give me an electric shock ?
Are you a lineman with the Electricity board ? You ...
Don 't come close or play games with me . Ill stab you .
That is Nakul 's wife Ganga .
I will hit you ... Don 't follow me .
You are coming from behind to scare me ?
What is it , Vasudha ?
What is it you want ? ... Tell me .
What is this you are doing ? If anybody sees us , it 's shameful .
It 's true , we are husband and wife , if you want III come home .
I said III come home . Trust me .
Leave me . What has happened to you to behave like this ?
If anyone sees us then we would rather die .
Sreedevi ...
Stop pulling me .
Where are you taking me ?
No one told me that they are coming back but yet
I keep my door half-open everyday .
Always , I wish someone dear to me will come .
It 's so quiet here . Such a nice atmosphere .
Do you like it here , Ganga ?
Of course , it 's so much better than what I had expected .
Aren 't you coming to sleep ?
Lm feeling sleepy . - You sleep .
Are all these books yours , sister ? - Let these be
kept here for now . We will shift them somewhere later .
What is it ? - Have you read this ? - Yes , Why ?
The author is my teacher in the college - Is it P. Mahadevan ?
He is ... - Then what ...
You know it . - No ... - Yes , you know .
Mother must have told everything to you .
What ? - Nothing , sister
Alli ! Wait ...
What is it ? Tell me , what 's the matter ?
My marriage has been fixed .
Why didn 't you tell me earlier ? Has everything been finalized .
Yes , in July . He stays in the adjacent house .
Where ? - See there .
I want a room to arrange all my books neatly .
I have been looking for one since yesterday .
There are so many rooms here . Come , III show you .
I don 't want just any room . I want a room with windows
looking out to the mango orchard . - Come , lets see .
No one ever comes here . - Come , let us see .
Sister , I think that room faces the East .
See , there is some talisman tied here .
Its locked too .
That 's alright . We can get the key from father .
Daughter ... - I think it is uncle . - Come , lets go .
Come , dear .
Where have you been ? - Upstairs .
This is an old house . There are certain limitations here .
There are rooms on the Southern side , where no one ever goes .
Those rooms have been locked up after certain Tantric rituals .
Every year during Durgashtami festival these rituals are done .
The souls of two youngsters who had untimely deaths were
exorcised and trapped in there .
Today 's youth might not believe it .
You don 't go there , That 's what , I came to tell you .
Why should we challenge the dead ?
Who were these people who died ?
Some 150 years ago there was a powerful Nobleman .
He brought a dancer from Tanjavur , and she stayed here .
Her name was Nagavalli . She loved a third person .
He was a dancer called Ramanathan .
Once he came in search of her and stayed in the adjacent house .
Somehow , the Nobleman got to Know of this .
That night he killed Nagavalli in that room upstairs .
It is said that on the night of Durgashtami her soul took the
form of a witch and entered that room to kill him .
The Nobleman chanted some powerful chants and was saved .
But after that her soul roamed this place day and night .
Then they brought a famous Tantrik , who performed rituals .
He managed to snare her soul into that room and secured it
with a powerful talisman .
Eventually the old nobleman too drank poison and died .
His soul too is trapped in the same room .
These are stories our grandmothers told us .
Who knows , what is the truth ?
Do you know who is staying now at the house Ramanathan stayed ?
It 's Allis fiancee , a college lecturer .
Your mother has often told me that there are many valuable
things in this house .
I 've looked everywhere but never saw a thing .
I think it might have all been kept in that locked room .
So that no one would enter to steal those things , all these
ghost stories may have been made up .
I want to open that room . What do you say ?
Open it if you want to .
They just came and gave the key .
Better open it before anyone comes here .
Shall I go now ? Have to go to college . I will come later .
Come once and see ...
Wont you seek the gate ? Please come ...
Let me get a glance of you today ...
Just once ...
Please fulfill my longing to see you ... Fulfill it .
That room has been barred and protected for a long time now .
Father too warned you , yet you got a key made to open it .
I came to stop you , but you seem to have opened it already .
It wasn 't the right thing to do . Now I wonder what will happen .
What is there to fear if I have opened a room in the house in
which we are staying is what I fail to understand .
Do you believe all this ?
How can I not believe ?
The locksmith who made this key is bedridden with sores on him .
And that boy , Chandu 's friend who took the key to be made
he is down with fever too .
I and Chandu will stay here for a few days just in case ...
If at all anything happens we will all bear it together .
Until I get this pooja done for repentance , and install this holy
vessel in that room and tie a holy thread , I will not get peace .
Someone is going to come this way one day . I know that .
A dear one will come this way is what I always wish for .
Even now it 's what I hope for today .
Many a time has the season of flowers lost its way
there are no flowers on the mango tree branches ...
For that alone there should be a season when it blooms .
I know there 's no one to come yet I wait at the door ...
Without knowing for whom it is , I wait inside the door expectantly
I wait expectantly .
A person dear to me will come is what I wish for always ...
With promises to meet again , he left me ...
I knew he would not come ...
But I stand at the main door regularly , waiting for him .
A person dear to me will come .
At the door like a statue I wait hoping you will come .
Unexpectedly , I felt that I heard someone 's footsteps .
The spring should bring something and remain forever .
If it should bring something ...
At times , I run with hope on to the path with eager eyes
someone who lost his way has come and gone ...
Will you sing a song in that Raga ?
Who are you ? - Me only , Nagavalli ...
Oh God ...
Nakul brother , Ganga ...
Wake up , someone is knocking at the door . I think it is Sreedevi .
What happened ?
Please come , the maid has seen something and she 's screaming
with fear . She is breathless and has a pain in her chest .
What is it ? ... What happened ?
She says she saw something that scared her .
What happened , Shanta ?
I heard the sound of anklets and woke up .
There she was at the window with her hair open .
You are just hallucinating . You think of all sorts of things
before sleeping and then get scared .
You can sleep in the next room if you are scared here ...
What happened ? - See , someone dropped it and it broke .
Don 't cause unnecessary problems .
Who is here to open her hair and walk , or break things ?
Don 't make up stories and lose your job .
Come ...
Sreedevi , you too ...
Chandu ! Who has arranged for all these people ?
It was Uncle .
Then ask Uncle to get rid of these people .
They are the ones who cause trouble saying things like
there are witches and ogres in Maadampally and ghosts ...
What 's all this ?
Chandu , you go to sleep . Well look into all this tomorrow .
Go ... you too Sreedevi .
Come , don 't be scared .
Let me speak first and you don 't tell me any excuses .
Just listen to what we say without any arguments .
What is it ?
You take Ganga and stay at some other place now itself .
Why ?
This house is a disturbed house .
You don 't have to stay to know the truth .
Let us conduct the necessary rituals , then you come back .
I am the only person to advise you in the absence of your mother .
There was something else that I wanted to speak to you about ...
Don 't back-answer . Just do as we say .
This is not the time to argue .
Uncle , since you have spoken so much , at least let me say ...
Its Ganga ...
Nakul ...
What happened ...
Her sari caught fire .
Ganga ...
Ganga ... What happened ?
Lie down . What happened ?
I don 't know how it happened ...
I came to know only after the sari had caught fire .
Where did it happen ?
I never went inside the kitchen , I was standing in the verandah .
Was there anyone else with you ?
There wasn 't anyone else , only I and Sreedevi .
Don 't get up now ... - Now I am okay , you can go .
Alli , give me a sari .
Uncle , can you please come here ?
What is it ?
Don 't mind my asking you , I have few doubts .
I can 't tell it to anyone else but you .
Please be clear about what you want to say to me .
I wanted to ask you if Sreedevi had any psychological problems .
If you have ever felt anything of the sort , be free to tell me .
We will show her to a psychiatrist .
What are you saying ?
You and that modern girl did things here which you should
not have done and so all this happened .
How can you hold Sreedevi responsible ?
Did you know what happened here last night ?
You would not agree to anything .
So I came here yesterday night to install a holy vessel in that
room without telling you .
Do you know what we saw ?
Would you believe it if I told you ?
We saw that dancer from the south with our own eyes .
Dasappan and the Tantri are witnesses .
Oh ! So you saw it too . Then there 's no room for doubt .
Everyone here is ...
What do I say ...
What senseless things , are you saying ?
What is wrong with Sreedevi ?
Since I am the head of the family there are a few things
I need to do here . After that you can come here to stay .
Will you or won 't you leave from here today ?
No , I and Ganga won 't go away no matter what anyone says .
You can do as you wish but I have also decided that
something needs to be done about Sreedevi .
What happened ? What 's the problem ?
He is not concerned about leaving .
He is not at all concerned about those blood-thirsty souls that
have been let loose .
According to him , it is my daughter , who has a problem .
Sreedevi ! What could be wrong with her ?
That 's something you had better ask him .
There 's no reason she should have a problem .
Now it was only this much , if I hadn 't noticed it could have
been more serious . Did you hear me well ?
We didn 't go near her . - Is it ?
No ... Don 't cause any more trouble here now .
Do not use the gas stove , you start using the kerosene stove .
What is it , uncle ?
No , it 's nothing .
What is it ?
Brother-in-law , listen to me , there 's something wrong with
Sreedevi . - What ? - Something is definitely wrong .
Yesterday , that Tamilian lady who came down from that room
won 't disappear just like that !
I have a doubt she has entered inside Sreedevi .
Yes ... Come and see for yourself .
What is it ?
It 's nothing . Nothing is wrong with you .
You continue swinging like that till morning .
What is it , father ?
Daughter !
What is it , mother ?
What is it Uncle , Aunt ? - Nothing .
You tell me what it is .
I want Dr. Sunny here . There is a lot of problem here .
Day by day the patient is going from bad to worse .
If he can 't help now then , what use in his being a psychiatrist .
Please inform him now .
Uncle had wanted Sreedevi and Nakul to get married .
But there was a problem in Sreedevi 's horoscope .
It was however a good match with his .
Yet Nakul 's mother was not happy and so she refused .
In revenge , uncle got Sreedevi married on the day of Nakul 's
... marriage to you without revealing the problem in her horoscope .
Finally when the groom came to know of it , he sent her back .
Since then Sreedevi is here .
Now after you all came , she was again happy .
But that too had to end like this . It is all ones destiny .
If the Tamil lady from the room has entered Sreedevi then the
nobleman , who came down with her must be around here .
No ... Don 't come for me I say . I will prick you .
I am only related by marriage to Basura , to this house .
I am telling you ... don 't come near .
Don 't come near me , nobleman .
I have already told you not to play with me .
I am just a relative and play with the many youngsters here
What is it ... What is it , Uncle ?
Uncle , What uncle , Which uncle ?
Who has let her loose ?
What happened , uncle ?
You don 't call me uncle . You Tamilian lady ...
Uncle ... - Don 't come near me . I am bad to the bad .
Don 't call me uncle and kill me . Just go away .
Someone save me !
Come fast , he 's killing me ...
Who is it ?
Oh , so it 's you !
Is this the mad person , you spoke of ?
He is very violent , he should have been locked up .
Lock me ...
Let him go ...
Don 't do anything to him , listen to me .
He says he is a senior member of the family .
What member , what senior ? He says he is Basuda 's husband .
Who is this Basuda ? - My wife and his aunt .
Let him go , he 's my uncle .
Oh , your uncle !
Yes , by marriage . - I am sorry . Don 't touch me .
Since you came to hit me with an umbrella I thought
there was something wrong with you .
Anyway , I am sorry , uncle .
He is a famous doctor from America .
He treats Psychic cases . - Psychiatrist ? !
Did you tell this madman there 's nothing wrong with me .
I mean the mad-peoples doctor ?
How did you land here ? I called everywhere to locate you .
Not without use ; now I am specializing in Mahendra hypnosis .
It is in great demand in America . My Lord !
Dear Sunny , tell me the truth . How did you come here ?
From the pilgrimage centre of Sabarimala .
You called my house , and they called Ramachandran .
I got news about your problem in Madras and flew down here .
Who 's that ? Your patient ...
No , a distant relative .
Relative ... Then via Madras , I came to Cochin , then to the
temple of Sabarimala , then Kottayam , then back here
by an auto-rickshaw .
Is this the patient ?
He is my maternal uncle .
Uncle ! He is the friend I spoke to you about , he 's a psychiatrist .
He has acquired a gold medal from America .
He is very famous , Dr. Sunny Joseph .
My daughter is not mad . You don 't make her one .
Then I came from place to place in an auto-rickshaw ...
What ? - No , nothing , then I came in this auto to your Maadampally .
What happened ? - Nothing . She came and peeped just now ... - Who ?
The one you told me about , Rashmi . - Oh ! Sreedevi !
But it 's difficult to treat and cure her . She is a little older .
You must have seen my aunt . - Your aunt !
You have a bath , change your robes , study the problems here .
Okay , III do all that , but there is enough time for that .
Where is your wife ?
Who is it ?
Ganga sister ...
Nakul brother ...
I 'll come too .
She 's inside here .
She will suffocate in there .
Break it ... 1 , 2 ... 3 ...
Tell me , Alli , what happened ?
When I went upstairs , I felt someone was following me .
I ran , I got into this room but someone locked it from outside .
Why did you go up ?
To look for sister Ganga .
Who told you , I was upstairs ?
Sister Sreedevi .
But she had seen me go for a bath downstairs .
Sunny , come with me .
You saw everything . These are the problems here .
What sort of behavior is this ? What does she mean by this ?
You understand the seriousness of it .
I 'll give you the Prasadam ( holy offerings ) .
Where is my bag ? All the Prasadam was in it .
Oh my God !
I vow by the name of God , III get the person who did this .
I will get him .
Stop , stop .
Where are you going ?
I am going to meet a tantric . After that night 's episode
there have been bad events happening in the house .
I am going to meet a famous tantric to ask him a solution .
You too can come .
Well , who 's this . Is it Padmanabhan Sir ?
Padmanabhan ! - No , not you ...
Oh , it 's you Unni Sir !
Who 's this ? Isn 't it Kunjankutty ?
Send him out . - Out ...
Go fast ...
You go get a talisman , there 's something wrong with you .
Who is this ? Is it Meenakshi ... Why you are in a scooter ?
Not a girl , but it is me , Dasappan , brother .
It 's you !
Brother , something wrong in Maadampally .
Our Sreedevi has become mad . - Well said . See me properly
There is some problem .
Sunny ... What are you looking for ?
Where is the bathroom ? - It 's there .
I have no Mundu , ( white garment worn around the waist ) .
Give me a mundu .
You go ahead , III send you one .
To the left ... - Yes
Where 's my Mundu ?
Who is it there , speak up ?
Who is there who took my Mundu ? Who is it ?
Who are you , girl ? - It 's not a she , it 's a he !
Who is he ? - It 's me . - Who me ? It 's me the doctor Sunny .
Okay . Give me back my Mundu .
I had come for my bath and taken it off .
I have worn it .
That 's not right . What do I wear now .
I 'll give it back to you now .
Did you recognize me ?
I wanted to see you .
Stop talking to me like that or else ...
When I saw you I knew you were not the right sort of person .
Give me back my clothes .
Wait , wait , no one need know .
Give me some time either in the morning or evening .
I 'll do whatever is possible .
You dog ... If you speak any more nonsense III show you .
If anyone passes by what would they say ! Give me my Mundu .
Here take it back . Don 't you allow a man to wear a mundu also ?
I came here in the afternoon .
We met outside the bathroom .
You never asked me my name .
Why didn 't you ask me , why I came here ?
I know you are the one who has come from America to treat me .
So , you know everything .
Okay , now the doctor is ready . But I need a patient too .
That 's why they have kept me here . All of you treat me .
So you agree ... you are the patient . That 's enough .
Don 't you want to sleep ?
Come , III show your room .
You don 't worry about where or when I sleep .
Just pretend I am not here .
Did you meet Sreedevi ? - Yes , but it is the primary stage .
We can cure that . You go sleep . Today there won 't be any trouble .
You can call us if you need anything . - Good night .
Sreedevi ... Sreedevi ...
Who is it ? ... Who is it ?
Who is it ? - Its Nakulan .
What is it ?
Nothing ... There was some ...
Wont you come once to my house to see me ?
Wont you show yourself today and fulfill my longing ?
I am a lady suffering due to your separation .
I am a lady who has none to adorn her with flowers .
I am like a bird stuck in net spread by someone and
I am trying to find my mate .
Wont you come at least once to my house to see me ?
Wait ...
Why were you roaming here ? - I had to go to the toilet .
Upstairs ! - No .
Then why did you run on seeing me ?
I wanted to go to the loo urgently .
When , where ...
To the loo ... - You do it here ... Yes , do it
I saw ... I saw the vessel .
Eeks ! - The vessel ...
It 's not right to roam at night ... Vessel .
I am saved . Vessel ... Vessel
Did you sleep here yesterday night ?
Yes , yesterday night after the dance performance , it was late ...
What dance performance ?
Who is learning classical dance here ? - Nobody here .
Yesterday night I heard someone upstairs dancing with anklets on .
With anklets ? - Yes - Did you really hear it ?
I heard it but I did not see the person .
The room to the far East .
But it is locked .
Why doesn 't someone sleep there at night ?
No . But that is not locked any longer and no one sleeps there .
Maybe , it was my imagination . Come , lets go and see .
Tea ? - III have it later . Give me my glasses .
This is not locked . - Not locked ... Yes ...
So this is the disputed room mentioned by Nakulan .
Isn 't he the cruel nobleman ?
He doesn 't seem to be a good person by his looks .
Where is the second party to all this , the dancer ? - Come .
See , it 's her .
So , I was wrong , Absolutely wrong . - What ?
That old man was a good person , a nice person . - What ?
If she is the dancer , who was also Ramanathan 's lover
then I won 't blame the old nobleman for kidnapping her .
What a structure !
Don 't you want to see the house where Ramanathan lived ?
See , there .
So this is where the girl Nagavalli used to sing ...
Come and see me once ... Come and meet me once ...
Don 't you want to see her ornaments ?
See ... A gold chain of jasmine - buds ! Mango shaped chain
A gold ring . A gold coin necklace .
An ornament worn on the head . Where are the anklets ?
It must be here somewhere . My tea must be cold ...
Have to go to the toilet ...
Stop there .
What is that sound when you walk ?
What is the tinkling sound when you walk ?
Anklets ...
From where did you get it ? - In the hall .
So that 's it ! You are the one who roams around here at night .
No ... - Then why did you put it in your pocket .
I wanted to know if it made a noise , if I put it in my pocket .
Is it ? Then , I will keep it .
Do you want it ? - No .
Then go ... Vessel ... - What ? - Vessel ...
How are you ?
Why did you call me yesterday night ?
It must be part of your treatment .
Whatever you feel , it is a good sign .
Even if you give the right answer I want to cross-check .
What is it ?
Don 't touch me , go .
What was he trying to do , putting his hands inside windows .
He 's not a good sort . He tried to flirt with me the day he came
Be careful !
Get up ... Lets go to the temple .
Well go later ...
Take Sreedevi too with you .
What ?
When you go to the temple , take Sreedevi with you .
What for ?
Don 't ask me why . I can say or do as I please .
Maybe I can sleep with the girl who was once to marry you .
Shall I ? You must consider it as part of the treatment .
Go to the temple , be close to her like you did in your youth .
Let me see and learn .
Is it necessary ?
Yes , absolutely . It 's necessary
It is needed , Nakulan .
Poor thing . Did you decide on the line of treatment ?
Consider all this as part of the treatment ... - Why ?
They are friends after all .
At this rate , you better think of getting married again .
What are you saying ? So that 's what you think of Nakulan .
I was just joking . Leave it .
You are always like this . You always find fault with everyone .
Yes , that 's right . I 'm seeing a lot of wrongs in the southern room
of Maadampally . - In the southern room ?
What is it ? - Nothing .
I think there 's a lot of shady things going on there .
There are many costly things in there ... Did you see this ?
This is Nagavalli 's anklet . Where did you get it from ?
You mean the 150 year old anklet ? - Yes .
Then you are wrong . This is not that one .
This is not even five years old . Which means the originals stolen
The anklet of Nagavalli has gone from the Southern room .
Where will it go ? This is the same one .
You may think so , but it is not the original one .
You keep quiet , Sunny . I have studied about old artifacts .
This is the Original one .
You know nothing . This is not Nagavalli 's anklet .
Yes , yes , yes .
And if it 's not ? - And if it is .
No , I say . - Yes , it is .
Who said so ? - I am saying it .
I have studied a lot about all this .
Well , So have I. It is not Nagavalli 's anklet
I say it is Nagavalli 's anklet . Don 't argue . - Who 's arguing ?
Is it me ? - No , it 's me .
Ill prove beyond doubt it is not her anklet .
You don 't know a thing .
Me , me , me ...
There 's no use arguing amongst ourselves . You go .
What is it ? What happened ?
She is arguing unnecessarily , as if all others are Idiots .
She maybe your wife , but I can 't accept ...
Why are you behaving like a kid ? Let it go . - Okay .
Why am I here without you ?
Can a fish live without water . By continuously looking at
the path , through which you 'll be coming , my eyes are tired
Can 't you hear the noise of the anklets of a dancer which
will tell you the story of a lady who is fading away .
Who is it ?
I am Sankaran Thambi .
You cruel man , Open the door .
Open the door . Open it ...
Who are you ?
You rascal , you ask me who I am . I am Nagavalli .
Why have you come ?
To kill you and drink your blood .
Open the door .
You cannot kill me Nagavalli .
Open the door . I am going to kill you this Durgashtami day .
Then only my revenge will be fulfilled .
Then come on Durgashtami .
Now you go , Nagavalli .
Now III go , but III be back . To kill you and drink your blood .
You don 't have to worry any more .
My previous life 's good deeds has made ...
The famous Tantric I spoke to you about has agreed to
take up this case . You need not worry any more .
He said if there 's any ritual to be performed ... - Sit
he will surely come here .
The Navaratri festival which was earlier conducted by our family
has to be conducted this time .
You don 't object . It 's important for the family .
I have no objections to holding any festival .
But I don 't want you to call tantrics to treat Sreedevi .
What are you saying ? You know nothing .
You have called some guy to treat Sreedevi . It 's not right .
He will give her an injection to make her unconscious .
And nothing is going to change . What is it ?
Look there , its him . - Where ?
There , there ...
How can we get rid of this guy ? He says he is a doctor .
What doctor ?
He will make us all mad . I say , ... where are you ?
What is it with you ? You seem to be wherever I go .
Come on ... up here .
What ? - What are you studying for ?
B.A. - What 's your second language ?
Indi - Oh , Indi . No , Hindi .
Then how come you know Tamil .
I ... Don 't play with me . I will hypnotize you .
Do you know music ? - No
Then how come you were singing in Tamil yesterday night ?
You look like a pretentious guy to me .
I have seen you in many suspicious circumstances .
I won 't spare you . What do you roam at night for ?
You want to go to the toilet all the time .
From where do you get all this urine .
Tell me the truth , If I start hypnotizing you , I can 't stop .
I want to help my sister . I know all of you will make her mad .
I know ...
No Chandu ... I was just joking .
I didn 't expect you to be so innocent .
I just can 't joke with anyone here
Here take this ... Everyone here is very serious ... Come ...
I am going to tell you something serious .
You don 't roam around here at night .
There is going to be an accident at your ancestral home .
Do I look like , I am joking ? It 's not a joke . It can happen .
Anytime today or tomorrow . Definitely before Durgashtami .
Only you know of it now . No one else should know .
What can be done ?
Lets see . Do you trust me ?
Yes - Then tell me where Yevur is ?
Yevur . That 's a bit far .
Both of us will go there today . Lets go get Allis cycle .
It 's about 10 to 20 kms . Away . Well go by bus .
Its only 20 kms . Away . Well go on cycle . Go get Allis cycle . Go fast ...
Many a time has the season of flowers lost its way
there are no flowers in the mango tree branches .
Someone who loves me will come ... the cuckoo sings ...
The cuckoo sings and says ...
Unexpectedly , I felt that I heard some footsteps
The spring should bring something and remain forever
If it should bring something .
Is no one , home ?
Who are you ?
We have come with a message from Brahmananda Namboodiri .
This is a list of things to be kept ready for the rituals .
Hell come here on the morning of Durgashtami .
So , there 's a problem ?
Hell tell you himself . He 's asked you to get everything in the list .
He has asked everyone of you including servants to be careful .
If anyone is ill , take special care of that person .
We will leave now . - Will you have something to eat ?
No ... - Or drink ?
The head priest has asked us not to eat anything from here .
Did you hear that ? What are we supposed to do now ?
Till the head priest comes , we have to take care of Sreedevi .
To take care of ... - Lock her up .
Why are you insisting on locking her up ?
Well decide what has to be done .
It 's better to lock her up .
You are the one who should be locked up .
You have come here , blowing your own trumpet from America .
Knives , penknives and axes . Are there any more of these here .
Where are you taking them all ?
We are going to have a collection .
I need it here for cooking
Just do as I say . Is that all ?
Here is the iron-prick for papadams .
Let it come .
Who has put it here ?
Nakula ...
Don 't drink that .
There 's poison in it .
I told you to lock up Sreedevi .
Lock up Sreedevi ...
No , don 't ... Father ... Father ...
No ... No ...
Open the door !
Open the door ! No ...
Open ... open ...
I won 't allow this . I won 't allow this .
Tell that doctor ...
Tell him to give me that poison and let me die . I will die . I won 't live .
Move ... Move ...
Did I do it ? Tell me ... did I do it ?
Tell me ... Did I do it ?
In the songs of times gone by , there was an old man
there was a bird dozing inside a historical room
filled with lot of sorrowful memories of love .
Oh beauty ! Are you lost in those memories ?
A soulful tune is reflected as a dream in your eyes .
The song of parting is here ... Even the veena is silent ...
The fallen branch felt the pain of separation .
The eyes and heart felt the same kind of darkness .
The bird entered the trap and locked itself ...
The bird entered the trap and locked itself
and has forgotten the lines in her song .
Chose to melt away like frozen dreams
there was a bird dozing inside a historical room
filled with lot of sorrowful memories of love .
Oh beauty ! Are you lost in those memories ?
A soulful tune is reflected as a dream in your eyes .
In the songs of times gone by , there was an old man ...
Has a snake doctor come from Africa ... No ...
Shantamma said that a mental doctor come from America
I want to see him - I am that fortunate one .
Rajappan and Kuttapan are saying that my behavior has changed .
Please check me , doctor .
Your behavior has some problem-Then start treating me
I will do it but after sometime .
I have locked someone in a room and started her treatment
After that I will attend to your case .
While going , do not touch water as water is dangerous to you .
Water ... There is water there See ... water
It has been a traditional family festival for years .
Once the head priest has said it must be revived , then it must be .
It 's just for three days .
Well all come together and make it a grand occasion . That 's all .
Didn 't you go to the temple to see the dance performance ?
It is a bore . I don 't want to go .
After staying in a village it wouldn 't be good not to see it .
Okay , well go .
And you ? I am ready . - Wait a minute .
Everyone has gone taking Sreedevi with them .
Why did they do that ?
Uncle insisted that all members of the family must participate
in all the functions . They are going to have some rituals too .
Anyway , lets see ...
Where is Ganga ?
Sunny , where is Ganga ?
Where 's Ganga ?
Come , lets look .
I didn 't do anything ... Listen to me ...
It was she ...
Leave me ... Listen to me ...
Listen to me ... I didn 't do anything . - Don 't talk
Nakulan , leave him ... Go and see Ganga . Go ...
I didn 't do anything . She only ...
I know , don 't worry ... Come ...
I had thought of telling you earlier , there are a lot of things .
... you need to know . You have to be very patient and listen to me .
The psychic patient who is trying to kill Alli , set Ganga 's sari
on fire is not Sreedevi ... That patient is your wife Ganga .
The day I came here , I knew that there was nothing wrong with
Sreedevi . When her illness was being projected , the real
patient was being hidden
I could not guess as to who it was .
Under those circumstances , I visited the Southern room with
Ganga . There I received a psychic vibration from her .
Painfully , I realized that the patient , I was looking out for
in Maadampally was Ganga .
From where and when did this illness come to Ganga ?
To test if it was as a result of jealousy
I asked you to take Sreedevi to the temple .
But Ganga was not at all affected by it .
Then I tried to instigate her by telling her Nagavalli 's tale .
When I disagreed with her about Nagavalli 's anklets , she retaliated
... strongly . I was unusually surprised to see the signs of her
... illness in her eyes strangely glowing in her eyes .
At that moment . She has changed like Nagavalli .
At sometimes , Ganga was changing as Nagavalli .
We hear in the newspapers that a eleven year old Muslim girl
... behaves like a twenty-one year old Brahmin woman and recites
... slokas . Old timers will say that a spirit has entered her .
In psychiatry , split personality , dual personality are the minor
illness which later leads to this kind of mental illness .
If she is not treated now the other person in her , Nagavalli
will surface . In this state of illness , she has great strength .
The woman Nagavalli , who wakes up next to you
At night knows how deep asleep you are and
when you will wake up . During the day she is with you and
without your knowledge burns up things .
At night , she who has
never learnt to dance sings Tamil songs and dances .
But she is not aware , that she is doing all this .
To know the depth of her illness I went to the southern room .
There I spoke to her as her psychic self .
The language was Tamil . There it started with Neurosis and went
on to become Psychosis . She was in a very murderous state .
To do something , I had to know about her childhood .
I Chandu went to the village of Yevur where she had spent
her childhood . There she had heard old stories from her
grandma , as a little girl . At the age of three , her parents
left her with her grandmother and went to pursue their jobs in
... Calcutta . She would sit everyday on the door-step waiting for
her parents . But they never came .
The year she was in Class ten , it was predicted that she would
get a merit and top the exams .
Then she received a letter from her parents .
They were going to get her admitted to a good
college in Calcutta . She was shattered .
She stopped studying and would pace restlessly up and down .
The sister recalled how on the day of her first exam , she tore
her paper and threw it and ran like a mad woman .
That was the first instance of psychotic behavior .
She sat with her grandmother when her parents came to take
her away . They took her to Calcutta where she may have
been treated by a doctor . She soon forgot her past and
became a part of Calcutta city . Yet , there was a possibility of
another psychic disorder hidden in her .
Then she got married . From your mother she heard of this village
and its tales . When she came here with you , she heard all the
superstitious stories here . At first she sympathized and then
empathized with the character of Nagavalli .
Her personality took the form of Nagavalli .
She was completely changing into Nagavalli mentally .
That has to be treated .
For that , she should never know that she is a patient .
Besides the three of us there is one other person who knows
of all this , which is Sreedevi .
Once when Ganga 's illness was threatened to be
revealed , I put Sreedevi in the room and locked it .
Then when I requested her , she agreed to act like a mad woman
for you and your wife 's sake a thousand times , if needed .
Nakul dear ...
Just open this door . Who has locked it ?
This is the dress I had taken off after coming from the temple .
It 's all torn and tattered .
It must have been Sreedevi .
Who else but her ?
How was the dance program yesterday ?
I didn 't see all of it . I cant recollect when I felt sleepy and
... came back home . Why , its Mahadevan ! When did you come ?
Sometime back .
That 's fine . How come you didn 't tell me , Nakul ?
Wait , III get some coffee .
What 's this , what 's all this ? What are you doing ?
Cool down ...
Come here for a minute .
The house you are currently staying at , was once the
house in which Ramanathan , the dancer stayed .
When the dormant character in Ganga , Nagavalli is awakened
you assume the place of Ramanathan for her .
Nakulan becomes the cruel Noble-man .
The rape-incident which you saw last night , was the drama
... enacted by the patient in Ganga . It was meant to look as if
you were trying to rape Ganga , and your marriage with Alli would
not be possible . She would then get you , that is Ramanathan back
This is how all the unnatural things that have happened
and are still happening have a reason and meaning .
All these are the strong codes which the patient in Ganga
has picked up , but these codes will never leave Ganga .
What does it mean ?
Tonight Ganga 's personality will change to that of Nagavalli 's
forever , that means as a total mad person .
Ganga will never be able to come back .
To come back from that illness there are just two ways .
Nakulan will be killed any minute , and Ganga will commit suicide .
I want to save Nakulan at least . - And Ganga ?
If I have to save Ganga , III have to sacrifice Nakulan .
If I save Nakulan , Ganga will commit suicide .
One death cannot be avoided .
Well have to erase at least one of them from our memory .
Unless some miracle occurs .
Greetings ! - Greetings ...
Come , I wanted to tell you a very important matter .
I was feeling very restless , till I could tell you .
Lets sit to the Northern side .
Sit . - So how has the festival in the family temple progressed ?
There have been no interruptions . Everything has gone on well .
It will get over tomorrow .
How about all the rites I have asked you to do ?
All those have been done properly .
That 's very good . I happened to consider your daughters
horoscope in detail . There is a certain problem there .
She might have some mental worries .
When I saw the position of the ancestral house I was shocked .
There is a great possibility of a untimely death here .
It 's not just that , in fact it has already occurred .
You don 't panic . By Gods grace It might pass off peacefully .
I feel , I have seen you somewhere .
I can 't recollect . Who 's this ? - He is ...
I 've forgotten where ... I can 't get it ... Detroit ... or ...
You have forgotten , head priest . We met in America .
Sunny ... why it 's you ! You cheated me .
How can I forget you ! I never imagined , Id see you here .
It 's a great surprise , you rascal . You 've put on weight .
When he was around why did you come and meet me with
your daughters problems . I think , you don 't know him well .
He is world famous . A wizard . The famous psychiatry teacher ...
Bradley was his Professor . When he wanted to declare a paper
on Para-psychology he invited me to America , at Delhi .
He was Bradley 's junior then . Did you know , two world famous
thesis on modern Psychology have been written by him .
There 's something I want to speak to you in private .
Okay , III be here today . We will only talk
Keep two chairs outside .
I have heard of many states of Psychosis , but it 's the first time
... I am hearing something this serious .
So this girl 's husband is still living with her . - Yes
Since he is your close friend can 't you tell him to stay away .
I assume that Ganga will be in her senses for another 20 hours .
At least let them be together till then .
What are you intending ? You tell him everything clearly .
Let him save himself .
No , there are still some more hours .
From my experience and love for you , let me tell you that its incurable .
I consider you as one of my teachers who have studied the
human mind . But I have to surpass all that I have learnt .
I will travel the paths not tried by any other psychiatrist .
For the sake of Nakulan and his wife .
I am going to break all conventional concepts of psychiatry
All right . I won 't discourage you . I am fully satisfied . You try .
What is the way ?
There are many ways to treating Ganga .
They will all lead to the regular outcome . I am not needed for it .
Ganga has heard stories of ghosts in her childhood .
There are stains of that which I have to wipe out .
I need your help for that . Then the atmosphere that you will
create for me . A world of rituals .
You be assured . Ill back you .
I have to start from a very dangerous time frame .
Don 't oppose me . Before tonight Ganga will realize , she is sick .
I am going to let her know it now .
You are afraid . I know . After that she won 't live for long .
She might die . But I 've decided that she should know that
she is a sick person through her husband .
If she survives that moment , I will have a path to follow .
In front of me . I can follow that path . You pray for me . Bless me .
Ganga is getting ready to buy ornaments for Alli .
You have to go and tell her not to go .
I have never stopped her from anything till today .
Then you must , today . Without any pity , tell her not to go .
Even if she resists you don 't give in .
If you notice any unnatural change in her , don 't panic .
You must use all your love and call her back . Go , now .
Okay ...
Where are you going ?
Didn 't I tell you , we are going to get ornaments for Allis marriage
You don 't go now . - I shouldn 't go . - No .
I had told you in the morning . Then why this sudden change of mind
You don 't go now , Ganga .
So , what if I too went to get ornaments for Alli ?
I told you that you should not go .
Why should I not go ? - Don 't go .
Wont you allow me ! Wont you allow me !
So you won 't let me go anywhere from here ?
You rogue , How dare you come and stand before me even now ?
Today is Durgashtami . I will kill you and drink your blood dance
Ganga ...
What did I just say ?
No , nothing ... you said nothing . - No , I said something
What 's wrong with me ? What 's happened to me ?
There 's nothing wrong with you .
No , there is . There is something wrong with me .
There 's nothing wrong with you , you don 't cry .
Please don 't hate me ...
You don 't hate me ... - Never , ever , my love ...
What do you want ?
Can I sleep ?
Sunny , what are you planning to do to my Ganga ?
Are you placing her in the hands of those Tantrics ?
I won 't let you . I will never allow that .
You listen to me .
No . You don 't speak a word . I saw her . I will take her .
Somewhere else . I won 't give her in your hands .
Listen to me .
You don 't say anything . It 's not possible .
No , leave me . Leave me , I say . She doesn 't need your treatment .
Go , go wherever you want to . But before you go , let me tell you .
No psychiatrist in this world can give her back to you .
I can also do what any psychiatrist can .
I can even give you a new Ganga .
But she will be just a stone image of your Ganga .
Is that enough for you ?
I want to give you back Ganga as we know her , full of life .
But for that you have to give me one more night , please .
Just this one night , please .
You take as many nights as you please . I just want her back .
I am going to do an experiment . Ganga might trouble you .
She might attack you , scratch you , try to kill you .
She might make permanent wounds in your heart .
Let anything happen to me . Let her do anything to me .
If she will kill me , let her . But you must give her back to me .
Give her back , Sunny - I 'll give you ... I 'll give you ...
Nagavalli that is Ganga has to be taken to that ritual site .
Only Mahadevan can do that .
Come once and see me ...
Did you come once to see me ?
Did you understand my mind and remove my sorrow ?
Did you embrace me with love , my beloved ...
I take your name every day .
Even though I know your heart , I search for you .
Did you come and see me once ?
The girl in your heart is dancing
My lotus eyes are dancing in my youth .
My curse has grown into the fiery love .
Many years of my penance has grown into fire of anger .
I got up ... to break all the obstacles in my way .
When this heart is waiting for you for ages
Can 't you come and see me once ?
Did you come and see me once ?
Did you recognize my mind ?
I won 't leave you . Let me go . Leave me .
I want to kill him . Leave me . You cruel man
Leave me ... Let me go , I want to kill him .
Leave me ...
Who are you ? - I won 't say .
Wont you say it ? - I won 't say .
I am Nagavalli .
Sit there . - No ... - Go sit on the seat .
Sit down there .
Why have you come ?
To kill . - Whom ?
To kill him .
Today is Durgashtami . I want to kill him and drink his blood .
I 'll help you to kill him .
After you kill him and you are avenged will you leave this body .
Yes ... - Promise ?
Promise , promise ...
Bring him here .
Leave me .
Leave me , Leave me , I am going to kill you and drink your blood
Today is Durgashtami , I am going to kill you , and drink your blood .
I am going to fulfill my revenge .
Leave me . I have to kill him .
Here ... kill him
Leave me .
You are hearing my voice in this subconscious mind .
The mind you can hear is yours , Ganga .
You are Ganga . You are Ganga .
In three seconds , you will return to your conscious mind .
Relax ...
Tell me , who are you ?
Tell me properly .
I am Ganga . - Tell me again .
You are now very happy . Very , very happy .
You have to realize that now you are free of your illness .
I understand . You are now going to wake up . Carefully wake up .
Do you know who we all are ?
Why do you ask me that , Sunny ?
You had an illness , a wonderful illness .
I have pulled it out from its roots .
You will never again have it . That 's my word .
I know , I trust you . Thank you , Sunny .
You might want to know all that happened .
In one of your private moments when the two of you are alone
Nakulan will tell you all like a story .
For a Ganga who likes hearing stories .
He need not tell me . I know it all .
I have a lot of people to thank like sister Sreedevi , but
most of all my Nakul whom I can never repay even if I take
many births for loving me so much .
Did you hear this Ganga you loved and who loves you a lot
and so full of life . I am giving her back to you . Take her .
Catch her ...
You two are fortunate . No other couple in this world have
understood each other in so much depth . This is the truth .
Now you can go to the Southern room as much as you want
or see anything . I still have some work left . - What is it ?
It 's difficult to stay with a mad man .
It 's even more difficult to live with one who treats madness .
If you are ready to bear the trouble , shall I send my mother here .
We Christians don 't have any problems with horoscopes .
Listen , III send mother ...
Where are you all going ?
I want to change as fast as possible for his sake .
For that Calcutta is more suitable . So we are going now .
Even I want to come .
You better come fast .
Chandu , this one too .
See you , Uncle .
When will the master return , I wonder ?
Don 't be so restless . The Tamil lady is now gone .
The old noble-man is still around . Be careful .
Now there 's nothing to fear .
Even if the noble-man stays here permanently we are happy .
Vessel ...
How are you now . No more jumping on water ? Let me see .
Put out your tongue .
Oh ! It was this . Ill fix it . The problem was here .
I felt as if a bird flew from here .
Now you can step on water .
And how about a bath ? - Yes , you can take bath .
Then there is no problem with me now . - No .
That means the illness is now gone .
It wasn 't an illness . Just a state of mind .
We call it Imacus canofia Tagadi .
Oh , so that 's what it was . I knew that .
Okay , see you then . - Ok ...
Okay , bye .
No , don 't . I like something . I 've told that to a person I like here .
When you know of it , you must agree and bless me ... Bye .
Just stop . Stop ! So did Sreedevi 's madness go away .
Actually it was not Sreedevi who was mad . - Then who ?
When hopefully you stand at the doorstep ...
The branch of the mango tree is full of blooms ...
My hearts mango tree branch is blossoming